Register of the Library of Social History Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Fourth International Series, 1894-1991 (Box 1-199)
  - United States
    - Subject file
      - Unemployed and relief movements
        - General
          - Pamphlets. Jack Martin, On Relief in Illinois; Herbert Benjamin, A Handbook for Project Workers, (1934) (1936) (Box-folder 193: 19)
          - Leaflets, 1932 (Box-folder 193: 20)
          - Miscellany, 1935 (Box-folder 193: 21)
        - National Committee of Unemployed Councils. Pamphlets. Poverty 'Midst Riches: Why?; Israel Amter, Industrial Slavery, (1931) (1933) (Box-folder 193: 22)
        - National Unemployed and Welfare Rights Organization (Box-folder 193: 23)
          - The Organizer. No. 4-5, n.n., (1973) (Box-folder 193: 24)
          - Leaflets, 1973 (Box-folder 193: 25)
        - National Unemployment Council. Constitution, 1934 (Box-folder 193: 26)
        - Public Works and Unemployment League [Los Angeles]. Unemployed Leader. No. 1, (1935) (Box-folder 194: 1)
        - Relief Workers' Protective Union [Los Angeles]. The Hunger Fighter. No. 1-2, (1933) (Box-folder 194: 2)
        - Unemployed Aid Society [Los Angeles]
          - Internal circulated documents, 1932 (Box-folder 194: 3)
          - Leaflets, 1932 (Box-folder 194: 4)
        - Unemployed Cooperative Relief Association [Los Angeles]
          - Among Ourselves. N.n., (1932) (Box-folder 194: 5)
          - News Bulletin. No. 1-2, 4-5, 9-10, (1933) (Box-folder 194: 6)
          - The Voice of the Rank and File. No. 1-10, (1933) (Box-folder 194: 7)
          - Internal circulated documents, 1932-1935 (Box-folder 194: 8)
          - Halstead, Frank. Typescript drafts of history of the movement, 1935 (Box-folder 194: 9)
          - Leaflets, n.d. (Box-folder 194: 10)
          - Press coverage, 1932 (Box-folder 194: 11)
        - Workers Alliance
          - Constitution, 1938 (Box-folder 194: 12)
          - Pamphlet. Como obtener trabajo con decente salario o un decente estandar de "relief"?, (1937) (Box-folder 194: 13)
        - Works Progress Administration strike [Minneapolis]. Press coverage, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 194: 14)
      - Women's movement
        - General
          - The Woman Activist. Vol. 3 no. 2-7, 9-10, n.n., vol. 4 no. 5, (1973) (1974) (Box-folder 194: 15)
          - Woman's Voice. No. 1, (1970) (Box-folder 194: 16)
          - Women: A Journal of Liberation. No. 3, (1970) (Box-folder 194: 17)
          - Women's Liberation Newsletter. No. 2, (1969) (Box-folder 194: 18)
          - Pamphlets. Wendell Phillips, Shall Women Have the Right to Vote?; Antoinette F. Konikow, Voluntary Motherhood; Marie Brant and Ellen Santori, A Woman's Place; Beverly Jones and Judith Brown, Toward a Female Liberation Movement; Marge Piercy, The Grand Coolie Dam; Lyn Wells, American Women: Their Use and Abuse; Our Bodies, Our Selves; The Racist Use of Rape and the Rape Charge; Woman and the Socialist Movement, (1910) (1938) (1953) (1968) (1969) (1969) (1970) (n.d.) (n.d.) (Box-folder 195: 1)
          - Leaflets, 1931-1976 (Box-folder 194: 2)
        - Committee for Abortion Rights and against Sterilization Abuse
          - News. Vol. 2 no. 5-7, (1978) (Box-folder 194: 3)
          - Pamphlet. Women under Attack: Abortion, Sterilization Abuse, and Reproductive Freedom, (1979) (Box-folder 194: 4)
        - Committee to Organize the Advancement of Women. Pamphlet. Mary Inman, Woman-Power, (1942) (Box-folder 195: 5)
        - Female Liberation [Organization]
          - Female Liberation Newsletter. N.n., (1969) (Box-folder 195: 6)
          - The Female State. No. 4, (1970) (Box-folder 195: 7)
          - No More Fun and Games. No. 2-3, (1969) (Box-folder 195: 8)
          - Internal circulated documents, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 195: 9)
          - Pamphlets. Knowledge and Control; The Right to Choose Abortion, (1970) (ca. 1971) (Box-folder 195: 10)
        - Feminists [Organization]
          - Internal circulated documents, 1969 (Box-folder 195: 11)
          - Leaflet, n.d. (Box-folder 195: 12)
        - National Organization for Women
          - Defending Women's Rights Newsletter. No. 1-5, no. 6, no. 7-10, (1977) (1977/1978) (1978) (Box-folder 195: 13)
          - Leaflets, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 195: 14)
        - New York Radical Feminists
          - Newsletter. No. 3, 5, (1971) (Box-folder 195: 15)
          - Internal circulated documents, 1971 (Box-folder 195: 16)
        - New York Radical Women. Pamphlets. Notes from the First Year; Notes from the Second Year: Women's Liberation; Notes from the Third Year: Women's Liberation, (1968) (1970) (1971) (Box-folder 195: 17)
        - Radical Women. Internal circulated document and miscellany, 1969 (Box-folder 196: 1)
        - Red Women's Detachment. Red Star. No. 4, no. 5, (1970) (1971) (Box-folder 196: 2)
        - Redstockings of the Women's Liberation Movement
          - Internal circulated documents, 1968-1975 (Box-folder 196: 3)
          - Pamphlet. Gloria Steinem and the CIA, (1975) (Box-folder 196: 4)
        - Union Women's Alliance to Gain Equality
          - Union W.A.G.E. No. 11, no. 26, no. 27, no. 38, (1972) (1974) (1975) (1976) (Box-folder 196: 5)
          - Union W.A.G.E. Newsletter. No. 4-5, 8, (1971) (Box-folder 196: 6)
        - Women's Rights Day, (1970)
          - Leaflets (Box-folder 196: 7)
          - Press coverage (Box-folder 196: 8)
  - Uruguay
    - Buró Latinoamericano [Fourth International]. Revista marxista latinoamericana. Vol. 5 no. 9, (1959) (Box-folder 196: 9)
    - Comité de Adhesió n a la Cuarta Internacional. Boletín trotskista. No. 2-3, supp., (1963) (Box-folder 196: 10)
    - Liga Obrera Revolucionaria
      - Contra la corriente. No. 8-9, no. 15, 17-20, no. 21-23, 25-26, supp., 27-29, no. 30, 32, 35, no. 36, 38, supp., 39-40, 42, 44, no. 46, (1942) (1943) (1944) (1945) (1946) (1947) (Box-folder 196: 11)
      - Frente obrero. No. 103, no. 105, supp., 107-108, (1955) (1956) (Box-folder 196: 12)
      - Nueva internacional. No. 2, (1942) (Box-folder 196: 13)
      - Internal circulated document, 1944 (Box-folder 196: 14)
      - Pamphlet. El trotskismo en Europa, (ca. 1944) (Box-folder 196: 15)
      - Leaflets, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 196: 16)
    - Liga Revolucionaria Internacionalista. Leaflet, 1943 (Box-folder 196: 17)
    - Liga Socialista Internacionalista. Contra la corriente. No. 2-3, (1941) (Box-folder 196: 18)
    - Partido Obrero Revolucionario (Trotskista). Frente obrero. No. 219, no. 231, no. 246, 252-254, 256, 258-259, no. 267, 269, 277, (1961) (1962) (1963) (1964) (Box-folder 196: 19)
    - Partido Revolucionario de los Trabajadores
      - Internal circulated documents, 1969 (Box-folder 196: 20)
      - Leaflets, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 196: 21)
    - Partido Socialista de los Trabajadores (Box 197)
      - Prensa obrera
        - Vol. 1 no. 1, 3-6, (1973) (Box-folder 197: 1)
        - Vol. 2 no. 1-3, 10, 14-16, (1974) (Box-folder 197: 2)
      - La verdad. No. 2, 4, (1977) (Box-folder 197: 3)
      - Pamphlet. Nuestro balance, (1982) (Box-folder 197: 4)
    - Tendencia Estudiantes Revolucionarios. Pamphlet. El movimiento estudiantil y sus tareas, (1971) (Box-folder 197: 5)
    - United Secretariat [Fourth International]
      - Boletín de informaciones latinoamericanas. N.n., no. 3, no. 4, 4 [sic], 5-6, (1967) (1968) (Box-folder 197: 6)
      - Cuadernos intercontinentales de informació n y análisis. N.n., (1968) (Box-folder 197: 7)
      - Revista de América. No. 2, (1970) (Box-folder 197: 8)
    - Unclassified by organization
      - Boletín de la resistencia oriental. No. 16, no. 17-21, supp., 23, 25, 27, n.n., no. 28-29, (1974) (1975) (1976) (Box-folder 197: 9)
      - Compañero. No. 1-2, no. 4, (1968) (1969) (Box-folder 197: 10)
      - Revolució n socialista. No. 11, (1981) (Box-folder 197: 11)
      - Surcos. No. 16, (1972) (Box-folder 197: 12)
  - Venezuela
    - Frente de Liberació n Nacional / Fuerzas Armadas de Liberació n Nacional
      - El combatiente. N.n., no. 15-18, (1969) (1971) (Box-folder 197: 13)
      - Venezuela en armas. No. 3, (1967) (Box-folder 197: 14)
      - Pamphlets. Documentos para la historia de América; Programa de acció n del Frente de liberació n nacional; Douglas Bravo, Documento de la montaña; Venezuela: por el camino de la liberació n, (1963) (1963) (1964) (1967) (Box-folder 197: 15)
    - Frente de Trabajadores Socialistas
      - La bujia. No. 1-3, (1977) (Box-folder 197: 16)
      - La inyectadora socialista. No. 3, 5, (1978) (Box-folder 197: 17)
      - Internal circulated documents, 1979 (Box-folder 197: 18)
      - Leaflets, 1978 (Box-folder 197: 19)
    - Frente Nacionalista Popular (Nueva Fuerza). Internal circulated document, n.d. (Box-folder 197: 20)
    - Juventud Comunista. Pamphlet. Proyecto de programa y estatutos de la Juventud comunista, ( n.d.) (Box-folder 197: 21)
    - Juventud del Movimiento al Socialismo. Leaflets, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 197: 22)
    - Liga Socialista
      - Boletín interno. No. 57, (1976) (Box-folder 197: 23)
      - El topo estudiantil. N.n., ( n.d.) (Box-folder 197: 24)
      - El topo obrero. No. 9, ( n.d.) (Box-folder 197: 25)
      - Internal circulated documents, 1975 (Box-folder 197: 26)
      - Leaflets, 1976 (Box-folder 197: 27)
    - Movimiento al Socialismo. Pamphlet. Teodoro Petkoff, Razones para una decisió n política, (1976) (Box-folder 198: 1)
    - Movimiento de Izquierda Revolucionaria
      - Carta de orientació n juvenil. No. 1, ( n.d.) (Box-folder 198: 2)
      - Pensamiento revolucionario. No. 2, (1961) (Box-folder 198: 3)
      - Interview with Domingo Alberto Rangel (typescript English translation), 1963 (Box-folder 198: 4)
      - Pamphlets. El rumbo hacia el socialismo; Fragmentos del informe político discutido por el Secretariado nacional del M.I.R., (1960) (1964) (Box-folder 198: 5)
    - Organizació n Socialista Revolucionaria
      - Boletín interno. No. 1, (1979) (Box-folder 198: 6)
      - Combate socialista. N.n., n.n., no. 4-6, no. 7-8, n.n., (1979) (1980) (1981) (1989) (Box-folder 198: 7)
      - Pamphlets. Las clases sociales en Venezuela; La cuestió n agraria y el movimiento campesino; Tendencia de la estructura econó mica venezolana; Cambios en la estructura social y lucha de clases en América latina; Las manifestaciones de la conciencia de clase en el movimiento obrero latinoamericano, (1981) (1981) (1981) (1982) (1982) (Box-folder 198: 8)
    - Partido de la Revolució n Venezolana. Fuego! No. 4/5, (1971) (Box-folder 198: 9)
    - Partido Socialista de los Trabajadores
      - Boletín interno. No. 1-3, 6, n.n., 10-11, 14, no. 15-16, 20-21, 25, (1973) (1974) (Box-folder 198: 10)
      - La chispa. No. 5-7, 12-13, no. 23, no. 46-48, (1981) (1982) (1984) (Box-folder 198: 11)
    - Política Proletaria. Pamphlet. La crisis del Comité de organizació n por la reconstrucció n de la Cuarta internacional (C.O.R.C.I.), (1979) (Box-folder 198: 12)
    - Tendencia pro Unidad Socialista
      - Boletín por la unidad socialista. No. 1-3, (1978) (Box-folder 198: 13)
      - El socialista. No. 1-2, (1978) (Box-folder 198: 14)
    - Unclassified by organization
      - Discusió n obrera. No. 1-2, (1979) (Box-folder 198: 15)
      - Dossier. No. 13, (1988) (Box-folder 198: 16)
      - Qué hacer? No. 1-8, 10-12, no. 55, (1974) (1975) (Box-folder 198: 17)
      - Unidentified internal circulated documents, 1963-1972 (Box-folder 198: 18)
      - Pamphlets. Moises Moleiro, El MIR de Venezuela; Edgar Gabaldó n Márquez, Venezuela, su imagen desvelada; Umberto Cerroni, Lenin, (1967) (1968) (1979) (Box-folder 198: 19)
  - Vietnam. United Secretariat [Fourth International]. Internal circulated documents, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 198: 20)
  - Zimbabwe
    - African National Council. Revolution. Vol. 2 no. 4, (1976) (Box-folder 198: 21)
    - Zimbabwe African People's Union. Pamphlet. George Nyandoro, Liberation Support Movement Interview, (1970) (Box-folder 198: 22)
  - Microfilm reels (Box 199)
    - French language material re Alsace: Le libérateur no. 1-2, no. 5, 7; Cahiers du bolchevisme no. 87; La lutte de classes no. 5. French language material re Indochina: La lutte de classes no. 20, no. 28-29, 31, (1929) (1930) (1927) (1928) (1930) (1931) (Box-folder 199: 1)
    - French language material: Bulletin international de l'Opposition communiste de gauche no. 1, no. 3, 5-13, no. 14, 16-17, 19, no. 1-3; Bulletin international de l'Opposition de gauche internationale no. 4-5; Bulletin de la Ligue communiste internationaliste no. 1-2, no. 3-4; Documents et discussions no. 1-2, (1930) (1931) (1932) (1933) (1933) (1933) (1934) (1934) (Box-folder 199: 2)
    - French language material: Bulletin de la Ligue communiste internationaliste no. 1-5, no. 7/8; Bulletin intérieur no. 1-4; Information; Service d'information et de presse n.n., n.n., no. 1-15/16, no. 17-21/22, (1935) (1936) (1935) (1935) (1935) (1936) (1937) (Box-folder 199: 3)
    - French language material: Bulletin intérieur n.n.; Bulletin intérieur international no. 1, no. 2-4; Bulletin international service d'information et de presse no. 1; Service d'information et de presse no. 1-2, 4, no. 5; Bulletin de la Quatrième internationale no. 4; Bulletin d'information Quatrième internationale n.n.; Bulletin du Comité pour la quatrième internationale no. 2. French language material re youth: Bulletin international des Jeunesses bolcheviks-leninistes no. 1-2; Bulletin international no. 1, no. 2, no. 3-4. Spanish language material: Boletín internacional de la Oposició n comunista de izquierda no. 1; Boletín de informació n no. 1-4, no. 5-7. Dutch language material: Informatie en discussiebulletin no. 1, 3; Intern internationaal bulletin no. 3, (1936) (1937) (1938) (1938) (1938) (1939) (1939) (1939) (1940) (1934) (1936) (1937) (1938) (1933) (1938) (1939) (1937) (1938) (Box-folder 199: 4)
    - German language material: Internationales Bulletin der Kommunistischen Links-Opposition no. 2, no. 3-6, 8-12, no. 13-19; Bulletin der Liga der Kommunisten-Internationalisten no. 1; Dokument zur Pariser Konferenz des London-Amsterdamer Buros; Bulletin der Internationalen Kommunistischen Liga no. 1-5; Bulletin der Deutschen Kommission n.n.; Inneres Bulletin der Internationalen Kommunistischen Liga no. 2; Internes internationales Bulletin no. 2-3; Thesen, Resolutionen und Aufrufe. German language material re youth: Internationale Jugendinformation vol. 1 no. 1-4, vol. 2 no. 1-2; Internationale Jugendinformation Pressedienst n.n.; Internationales Jugend-Bulletin vol. 3 no. 3, (1930) (1931) (1932) (1934) (1935) (1935) (1935) (1935) (1938) (1936) (1935) (1936) (1936) (1936) (Box-folder 199: 5)
    - Russian language material: Voprosy kultury pri diktature proletariata, (1925) (Box-folder 199: 6)
    - Russian language material: Boevaia pravda no. 195, 228; Derevenskaia kommuna no. 230-231; Rabochaia Moskva no. 39, 41, 94, 102, (1920) (1920) (1923) (Box-folder 199: 7)
- Cuban Revolutionary Government Series, 1931-1992 (Box 200-248)
  Speeches and writings by leaders of the Cuban revolutionary government. Arranged by author. Includes some additional serial issues, pamphlets, and conference proceedings issued by Cuban government agencies or relating to Cuba.
  - Individual speeches and writings. Printed unless otherwise indicated
    - Aldana Escalante, Carlos (secretary, Comité Central, Partido Comunista)
      - Speech, Unión Nacional de Escritores y Artistas congress, 1988 January 28 (Box-folder 200: 1)
        Spanish (processed), English (printed)
      - Remarks, meeting re radio and television media, 1988 March 11 (Box-folder 200: 2)
        Spanish
      - Remarks, Asociación Hermanos Saiz meeting, 1988 March 12 (Box-folder 200: 3)
      - Remarks, Asociación Hermanos Saiz meeting, 1988 May 28 (Box-folder 200: 4)
      - Speech re Bohemia, 1988 May (Box-folder 200: 5)
      - Interview with El diario, 1988 December 23 (Box-folder 200: 6)
      - Remarks, Unión de Periodistas meeting, 1989 March 14 (Box-folder 200: 7)
        Spanish, English
      - Remarks, meeting of newspaper directors of socialist countries, Havana, 1989 April (Box-folder 200: 8)
        English
      - Interview with Granma, 1989 May 21 (Box-folder 200: 9)
      - Interview with El militante comunista, 1989 June (Box-folder 200: 10)
      - Interview with Granma, 1989 June 9 (Box-folder 200: 11)
      - Remarks, meeting re visual media, 1989 September 21 (Box-folder 200: 12)
      - Interview with El diario, 1990 February (Box-folder 200: 13)
      - Interview with Granma, 1990 April (Box-folder 200: 14)
      - Interview with Analisis (Chile), 1991 January (Box-folder 200: 15)
      - Remarks, 1991 February (Box-folder 200: 16)
      - Interview with Granma, 1991 March (Box-folder 200: 17)
      - Interview with Excelsior (Mexico), 1991 July (Box-folder 200: 18)
      - Speech, Asamblea Nacional del Poder Popular, 1991 December 27 (Box-folder 200: 19)
    - Almeida Bosque, Juan (leading member, Partido Comunista)
      - Remarks, 1960 July 10 (Box-folder 200: 20)
      - Speech, May Day, 1967 May 1 (Box-folder 200: 21)
      - Speech, funeral of Haydée Santamaría, 1980 July 29 (Box-folder 200: 22)
    - Botí León, Regino (minister of economy). Speech re U.S. investment in Latin America, Inter-American Social and Economic Council meeting, Bogota, Colombia, 1960 September 7 (Box-folder 200: 23)
    - Cabrera, Guillermo (ideological secretary, Unión de Jóvenes Comunistas). Protagonistas del Realengo, (1972) (Box-folder 200: 24)
    - Castro Ruz, Fidel (prime minister; president; first secretary, Partido Comunista)
      - General. Bibliographical notes, publishing proposals (Box-folder 200: 25)
      - Defense speech, trial after Moncada barracks attack, 1953 October 16 (Box-folder 200: 26)
      - Manifesto from prison, 1953 December 12 (Box-folder 200: 27)
      - Letter to Luis Conte Agüero, 1955 March (Box-folder 200: 28)
      - Letter to Carmen Castro Porta, 1955 September 17 (Box-folder 200: 29)
      - "Frente a todos!", 1955 December 25 (Box-folder 200: 30)
      - Manifesto of Movimiento 26 de Julio, 1956 March 19 (Box-folder 200: 31)
      - Letter to Miguel Angel Quevedo, 1956 August 26 (Box-folder 200: 32)
      - Letter to Frank País, 1957 July 21 (Box-folder 200: 33)
      - Letter to Junta de Liberación Cubana (Miami), 1957 December 14 (Box-folder 200: 34)
      - Letter to Cubans in exile, 1958 January 9 (Box-folder 200: 35)
      - Interview with Andrew St. George ( Coronet), 1958 February 4 (Box-folder 200: 36)
      - Manifesto of Movimiento 26 de Julio, 1958 March 12 (Box-folder 200: 37)
      - Radio address, Radio Rebelde, 1958 April 15 (Box-folder 200: 38)
      - Response to questionnaire of Jules Dubois ( Chicago Tribune), 1958 May 16 (Box-folder 200: 39)
      - Unification declaration of Cuban oppositionists, Caracas, Venezuela, 1958 July 20 (Box-folder 200: 40)
      - Radio address, Radio Rebelde, 1958 July 20-21 (Box-folder 200: 41)
      - Communiqué re Battle of El Jigüe, 1958 July 24 (Box-folder 200: 42)
      - Radio address, Radio Rebelde, 1958 August 18-19 (Box-folder 200: 43)
      - Radio address, Radio Rebelde, 1958 October 25 (Box-folder 200: 44)
      - Letter to Radio Rebelde personnel, 1958 November 26 (Box-folder 200: 45)
      - Communiqué re Battle of Guisa, 1958 December 1 (Box-folder 200: 46)
      - Military orders, Radio Rebelde, 1959 January 1 (Box-folder 200: 47)
      - Speech, entry into Santiago, 1959 January 2 (Box-folder 200: 48)
      - Speech, Campamento de Columbia, 1959 January 8 (Box-folder 200: 49)
      - Speech, Havana, 1959 January 21 (Box-folder 200: 50)
      - Speech to Shell Oil Company of Cuba workers, 1959 February 6 (Box-folder 200: 51)
      - Speech, Federación Nacional de Trabajadores Azucareros meeting, 1959 February 9 (Box-folder 200: 52)
      - Letter to Jules Dubois, 1959 February 14 (Box-folder 200: 53)
      - Inaugural speech as prime minister, 1959 February 16 (Box-folder 200: 54)
      - Remarks, televised press conference, 1959 February 19 (Box-folder 200: 55)
      - Speech to peasants, 1959 February 24 (Box-folder 200: 56)
      - Speech, Holguín, 1959 February 26 (Box-folder 200: 57)
      - Speech, 1959 March 22 (Box-folder 201: 1)
      - Speech, 1959 March 25 (Box-folder 201: 2)
      - Remarks, televised press conference, 1959 April 2 (Box-folder 201: 3)
      - Speech, New York, New York, 1959 April 22 (Box-folder 201: 4)
      - Speech, Organization of American States Economic Council meeting, Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1959 May 2 (Box-folder 201: 5)
        Spanish (mimeograph), English (mimeograph, printed)
      - Speech re agrarian reform, 1959 June 21 (Box-folder 201: 6)
      - Speech, Confederación de Trabajadores meeting, 1959 September 13 (Box-folder 201: 7)
      - Speech to children, conversion of fortress to school, 1959 September 14 (Box-folder 201: 8)
      - Remarks, televised press conference on the economy, 1959 September 17 (Box-folder 201: 9)
      - Speech, conversion of fortress to school, 1959 October 21 (Box-folder 201: 10)
      - Speech re aerial attack on Havana, 1959 October 26 (Box-folder 201: 11)
        Spanish (printed), English (mimeograph)
      - Remarks, televised press conference on the disappearance of Camilo Cienfuegos, 1959 November 12 (Box-folder 201: 12)
      - Speeches, Confederación de Trabajadores congress, November 18 and 23, 1959 (Box-folder 201: 13)
      - Statement, trial of Huber Matos, 1959 December 14 (Box-folder 201: 14)
      - Speech, Federación Nacional de Trabajadores Azucareros congress, 1959 December 15 (Box-folder 201: 15)
      - Guia del pensamiento político económico de Fidel [pamphlet compendium of excerpts from speeches and writings], (1959) (Box-folder 201: 16)
      - Speech, conversion of police station to school, 1960 January 10 (Box-folder 201: 17)
      - Speech, conversion of Moncada barracks to school, 1960 January 28 (Box-folder 201: 18)
      - Speech, conversion of fortress to school, 1960 February 24 (Box-folder 201: 19)
      - Speech re salary contributions to industrialization program, Confederación de Trabajadores meeting, 1960 February 24 (Box-folder 201: 20)
      - Speech, funeral of victims of explosion of ship La Coubre, 1960 March 5 (Box-folder 201: 21)
      - Speech, Federació n Nacional de Trabajadores Azurareros meeting, 1960 March 27 (Box-folder 201: 22)
      - Remarks, televised press conference, 1960 March 28 (Box-folder 201: 23)
        Spanish (mimeograph)
      - Interview with Richard Bates (CBS), 1960 April 19 (Box-folder 202: 1)
      - Speech, May Day, 1960 May 1 (Box-folder 202: 2)
      - Remarks, televised press conference re danger of attack, 1960 May 13 (Box-folder 202: 3)
      - Televised speech on anniversary of agrarian reform, 1960 May 17 (Box-folder 202: 4)
      - Speech, Pinar del Rio, 1960 May 20 (Box-folder 202: 5)
      - Remarks, televised press conference, 1960 May 27 (Box-folder 202: 6)
      - Speech, Trabajadores de la Construcción congress, 1960 May 29 (Box-folder 202: 7)
      - Speech, Asamblea de Empleados y Obreros del Comercio, 1960 June 4 (Box-folder 202: 8)
      - Speech, Federación Nacional de Trabajadores de Barberías y Pulquerías congress, 1960 June 10 (Box-folder 202: 9)
      - Remarks, televised press conference re trade agreement with Czechoslovakia, 1960 June 10 (Box-folder 202: 10)
      - Speech, appearance with Osvaldo Dorticós, 1960 June 14 (Box-folder 202: 11)
      - Speech to food workers, 1960 June 15 (Box-folder 202: 12)
      - Remarks, televised press conference re sugar industry and relations with U.S., 1960 June 24 (Box-folder 202: 13)
      - Speech, symposium on national defense, 1960 June 26 (Box-folder 202: 14)
      - Speech, Confederación de Trabajadores meeting, 1960 July 6 (Box-folder 202: 15)
      - Remarks, televised press conference, 1960 July 8 (Box-folder 202: 16)